本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
哦  占尽了优势
Oh! Total domination!
我简直就是阁楼版迷你高尔夫的大师呀
I am the master of attic-stuff mini-golf!
从雄伟的瑞士阿尔卑斯山
From the mighty Swiss Alps
到人人都害怕踩到的由迪普的脏衣服
to the badlands of Dipper's old laundry,
堆成的荒地
where man fears to tread.
行了  让我这个专家上草坪吧
All right, let a pro on the field.
呃  地板  随便吧
Er...floor. Whatever.
我的头
Ow! My head!
正好打在我的头上
It hit me right in the head!
太棒了  打中斯坦了
Yes! Stan shot!
不算犯规吧
Is that legal?
裁判说那一杆出界了
The judges say it's out of bounds.
你才出界了
You're out of bounds!
嘿  别这样
Hey! Stop it!
嘿  迪普  我今晚要和糖糖还有格兰达一起玩
Hey, Dipper, I gotta go hang out with Candy and Grenda tonight.
又去玩  你不能中途离开赛场
Aw, again? You can't leave mid-game!
别傻了  我没有要走啊
Don't be silly, I'm not leaving!
我的朋友们来找我玩
My friends are coming to me!
等等  什么
Wait, what?
不  不  不  不 不
Oh, no. No, no, no.
睡袋  DVD光盘
Sleeping bags? Rom-coms?
打电话给所有的男孩的青少年版
Calling all boys preteen edition?!
你不会是要开
You're not having a--
睡衣派对
Sleep over!
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
CC录制： ufohaman  Qin Cong
时间轴： sunshine
■
翻译： Focus  Tracy
校订： Enpistu  WaitinZ
■
后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第一季第十六集
Gravity Falls  S01E16  Carpet Diem
好了  你究竟有多喜欢男孩子
Okay, so how much do you like boys?
好喜欢
So much!
男孩子们让我联想到亲亲
Boys make me think about kissing.
糖糖
Candy!
我的老天啊
Oh my gosh! Ow!
我们今晚好疯狂啊
We are so crazy tonight!
有谁想在我脸上化化妆
Who wants to smear make-up on my face?
哦  你已经很美了格兰达
Oh, you're already so beautiful Grenda,
化妆还有什么意义呢
What would be the point?
变漂亮  变漂亮
Beautiful! Beautiful!
我要变美
Beautiful!
梅宝
Mabel!
你不觉得你们应该去别的地方玩吗
Do you think you could do this somewhere else?
你们大笑的频率只有狗才能接受啊
You're laughing at frequencies only dogs should hear.
拜托  哪有那么吵
Come on, it's not that bad.
你知道你弟弟需要什么吗
You know what your brother needs?
美妆大改造
A makeover?
嘿  苏斯  我今晚能睡在你的休息室吗
Hey Soos, can I sleep in your break room tonight?
当然了  哥们
Of course, dude.
你只要把你的身体调整到
You just gotta make your body
像俄罗斯方块填补空缺一样就行了
go like a video game puzzle block.
技巧就是要完全控制你的身体保持不动
The trick is to hold perfectly still.
哦  不对  不对
Oh! Wait, wait.
哦  再等等
哦  等等
Oh! Wait, wait. Ow, ow, ow--
我想我还是去别的地方睡吧
I think I'll sleep somewhere else.
刚那次感觉还不错
Actually felt good that time.
哦  等等
Ow! Wait, wait.
躺望星空  也不算坏
Sleeping under the stars... not bad.
啊  放开我
Ah! Get off!
快走开
Ah! Ah! Get away!
总比那里好些
This is still better.
呃   昨晚发生了什么
Uhh... what happened last night?
早上好啊  派对姑娘
What's up, party girl?
我不知道我亲了什么东西
I don't know what I was kissing in there,
但我一点都不后悔
But I have no regrets.
糖糖要下落咯
Candy falls down now!
昨晚是太棒了  姑娘们
That was awesome, girls!
回见呀
See you again soon!
嘿老弟
Hey brother!
你想要尝尝这片隔夜的披萨么
You want any of this leftover pizza?
它还在闪光哦
It's got glitter on it!
梅宝  昨晚一只猫头鹰差点吃掉我的舌头
Mabel, last night an owl tried to eat my tongue.
真不错
That's great!
不  一点也不好
No, it's not great!
这地方没人能住得下去
This is impossible to live with!
什么  跟我住就很欢乐呀
What? I'm delightful to live with!
准备好被这根有趣的树枝戳吧
Get ready to be poked by the fun stick!
-我戳  -啊
- Boop. - Ahh!
梅宝  我受够了这可笑的树枝了
Mabel, I've had it with the fun stick!
你完全毁了我们的房间
You've totally wrecked our room.
还有  哦  不
And... oh no!
我们的迷你高尔夫球场
Our mini golf course!
是啊  格兰达就是喜欢毁坏东西
Yeah, Grenda sure loves breaking things.
梅宝  如果我们还要继续一起住在这间房间里
Mabel, we need to lay down some ground rules
必须得约法三章了
if we're gonna be living in this room together.
首先  禁止睡衣派对
First of all, no sleepovers.
什么
What?!
好吧  如果我们不能开睡衣派对
Well if I can't have sleepovers,
那你也不能每晚读书时打扰我睡觉
then you can't keep me up every night with your summer reading.
我看书怎么打扰你了
How does reading keep you up?
神探表兄弟之酸豆盒子里的酸豆疑案
有意思
Interesting...
但是究竟谁偷了酸豆呢
But who stole the capers?
好吧  但至少我的牙套不会在我呼吸的时候发声
Well, at least my braces don't whistle when I breathe!
那至少我还会偶尔洗我的衣服
At least I wash my clothes once in a while!
洗衣服简直就是浪费时间
Washing clothes is a waste of time!
我可忙了
I'm a busy guy!
行行  你要是敢再喵一次
All right. If you meow one more time--
好吧  就这样了  我也受够了
Okay, that's it, that's the final straw.
也许我们不该再睡一个房间了
Maybe we shouldn't share a room anymore.
这样  呃
Well, uh--
嗯  也许我们是不该
Well, maybe we shouldn't!
-我同意  -我也同意
- Fine by me! - Double fine by me!
那我们只要去跟斯坦叔公说一声搬房间的事就行了
Then we need to talk to grunkle Stan about moving rooms.
是啊  他最讲道理了
Yeah, he's a reasonable guy.
打啊  打啊  打啊
Fight! Fight! Fight!
打起来  打起来  打起来
宝宝战争
电视  总知道我想看什么
TV, it knows what I want.
斯坦叔公  我们想要分开住
Grunkle Stan? We want different rooms.
我还想要一条魔法金钱裤呢
And I want a pair of magic money pants!
这是不可能的
It's not gonna happen.
魔法金钱裤
Magic money pants?
拜托啦  斯坦叔公
Come on, grunkle Stan!
我们不能想想办法吗
Can't we work something out?
瞧着  孩子  只有我的房间和阁楼了
Look, kid. There's my room and the attic.
就这些  你们觉得呢
That's it. What do you think,
难道在小屋什么隐蔽的地方还有密室什么的吗
there's some kind of secret hidden room in the shack?
伙计们
Dudes!
我在小屋的一个隐蔽的地方找到间密室
I found some kind of secret hidden room in the shack!
好吧  刚才我只是在清理这个书架的背面
Okay, so I was cleaning up behind this bookcase,
然后砰地一声  出现了这扇神秘的门
when boom! Mystery door.
这间老屋子充满了奇怪的秘密
This old shack is full of weird secrets.
漂亮
Classy!
78号实验
"Experiment 78."
斯坦叔公  这是什么地方
Grunkle Stan, what is this place?
我不知道
I don't know.
不过又是个我要清理的房间罢了
Just another room I gotta clean up now.
这地毯真棒
The carpet it's amazing!
是啊  如果你喜欢差劲东西的话
Yeah, if you're into things that are terrible.
问题解决了  我要住到这里来
Problem solved! I'll move in here!
什么  凭什么你就顺理成章地得到这房间了
What? Why do you automatically get the room?
这是我们同时看见的
We both saw it at the same time!
等一下
Wait a second...
你们都想要这个房间对吗
So you both want this room, huh?
我想我会把它给
I guess I'll give it to
你们中我最喜欢的那个
whichever one of you I like more.
哦  不  我的鞋带松了呢
Uh oh. Looks like my shoe's untied!
我来
Give it to me.
去厨房  打起来  打起来
To the kitchen! Fight! Fight!
打啊  打啊
Fight! Fight!
我不明白  伙计们
Whoa. I don't know dudes.
这间房间总给我种很诡异的感觉
This room gives me major creep-o vibes.
你看  其实阁楼是个相当不错的地方
Ya know, the attic is a pretty good space.
也许你们俩应该珍惜你们所拥有的
Maybe you two should appreciate what you got.
斯坦叔公  我要这间房间
Grunkle Stan! I gotta have that room!
呵  嘿  我也说不准
Huh. Hey, what do I know?
也许这房间不会发生什么诡异的事
Maybe there's nothing creepy going on in this room.
好吧  孩子们  我有个办法
All right, kids, here's how it's gonna go down.
谁马屁拍得最厉害  我就把钥匙给谁
Whoever sucks up the hardest, gets the key to the new room.
斯坦叔公  我们才不会为了一个新房间
Grunkle Stan, we're not going to suck up to you
来拍你的马屁的
just to get the new room.
是  我们会的
Yeah, we are!
梅宝得到了十个马屁积分
Ten suck up points for Mabel!
我是说  是啊  我们会的
I mean, uh, yeah we are!
太做作了  扣十五个马屁积分
Trying too hard. Minus 15 suck up points.
-什么  -英明  斯坦叔公
- What? - Good decision, grunkle Stan!
够做作啊  再加五十分
Trying way too hard! Plus 50 suck up points.
谁想顶着四十度的高温去
Now who wants to re-tile the roof
重新盖一下屋顶呢
In searing 105 degree heat!
我  我  我来
Me! Me! I'll do it!
我  不  迪普  拿过来
Me! No, Dipper! Give it here!
斯坦  你真是个好叔公
Ahh, Stan, you're a good uncle.
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
迪普  你还不够卖力啊
Dipper! You're phoning it in!
啊  老天  真清新啊
Ahh. Man, that's refreshing.
给这杯柠檬汁加十分
Ten suck up points for this lemonade.
谢谢你  斯坦
Thank you, Stan.
再加十分奖励你这么有礼貌
Oh, ho! Ten more for politeness.
真甜哪
Oh, and so sweet!
等我得到这间房间  我所做的一切就都值了
All these chores will be worth it when I get this room.
蓬松的地毯  太棒了
Shag carpeting... come on!
嘿  老弟  别太舒服了
Hey, brother. Don't get too comfortable,
我刚给斯坦做了一个形状像他的脸一样的煎蛋卷
I just made Stan an omelet shaped like his own face.
这是我见过最美的脸
I have seen the face of beauty.
面对现实吧  我就是个马屁精啊
Face it. I'm like a suck up ninja!
这间房间就像我自己的一样
This room's as good as mine!
你最好现在就放弃吧
You might as well give up now.
你觉得怎么样
What do you say?
我说  不管怎样我都要赢下这个房间
I say, I'm gonna win this room somehow,
等到那时候
And when I do...
我终于有了自己的空间
I'll finally have my own space,
我们就再也不用分享任何东西了
And we'll never have to share anything ever again!
发生什么了
Ugh...what happened?
迪普
Dipper?
为什么你穿着我的衣服
Why are you wearing my clothes?
还长着  我的脸
And my... face!?
我在你身体里吗
Am I in my your body?
出去  出去啊
Get out! Get out!
快出去
Get out!
这不是真的
This isn't happening.
这不是真的  这不是真的
This isn't happening. This isn't happening.
太好了  这正是我们想要的
Great, just what we need.
更多的重力泉离奇事件
More gravity falls weirdness.
这太愚蠢了
This is stupid!
共用一间房间已经够糟的了
Sharing a room was bad enough.
现在还要共用身体吗
Now we're sharing bodies?
牙套真讨厌
Ugh, braces are horrible.
感觉我的嘴巴讨厌我
It's like my mouth hates me!
这些是什么啊
And what are these things?
我想知道你为什么这么汗渍渍的
I wanna know why you're so sweaty!
-那么笨拙  -嘿  看啊
- And awkward. - Hey, look!
78号实验
Experiment 78!
电子地毯
Electron carpet.
原子能交换电子
Atoms can swap electrons.
这个地毯一定加强了静电荷
This carpet must build up a static charge
以至于能互换灵魂
so powerful it can swap minds.
是静电的缘故
It was the static electricity.
也许  我们还能用它换回去
Maybe, we could use it to switch back!
哦  还好
Phew. Oh, oh!
真高兴我又能换回去了
Glad I'm switchin' back.
如果我是你的话  我一定会输了这场比赛的
If I was you, I would totally lose the contest.
如果我是你  那我就
And if I was you, which I am...
我可以陷害我自己
I could sabotage myself!
让梅宝丢光所有分数
Then Mabel would lose all her points
这样房间就归迪普了
and the room would go to Dipper!
等等  什么
Wait, what?
哦  斯坦
Oh, Stan!
我一直都好讨厌你
I've always hated you!
哈哈  看看现在他会把房间给谁呢
Ha ha! See who he gives the room to now!
不  等等
No! Wait!
系好你的鞋带
Tie your shoes!!
那些食人族的行为还是有道理的
Mmm... those cannibals are onto something,
我的味道棒极了
I taste delicious!
斯坦叔公
Grunkle Stan!
什么事啊  梅宝
What's the word, Mabel?
是啊  是我  梅宝
That's right! It's me, ugh, Mabel!
如果你喜欢刚刚那个煎蛋卷  那你一定会喜欢这个
If you like that omelet, you'll love this...
一个用石头做的三明治
A sandwich made out of rocks!
石头糖果
Candy rocks?
普通的石头
Regular rocks!
继续这样下去  我会把钥匙给你弟弟的
Keep that up, and I'll be giving your brother this key.
哈哈  我是说  可恶啊
Ha ha! I mean... darn.
嘿  斯坦叔公
Hey, grunkle Stan!
你的脸看起来像个屁股
Your face looks like a butt!
什么
What?!
破坏东西真有趣
Breaking stuff is so much fun!
我是迪普我好臭
I am Dipper and I stink!
梅宝发疯啦
Mabel's gone bananas!
好吧  这有些奇怪啊
Well, this is getting weird.
等等
Wait!
你不扣梅宝的分数吗
Are you gonna dock Mabel points?
迪普的全部分数都该扣掉
Dipper should lose all his points!
斯坦叔公
Ugh! Grunkle Stan!
摇摇  你的生活还真快乐
Waddles, you got it good, bro.
都没有烦恼
You got no worries.
如果我也光着身子躺在客厅的地板上
I mean, nobody thinks it's cute
人们肯定认为我疯了
When I lie naked on the living room floor.
希望我也能做头猪
I wish I could be a pig.
太棒了
Yes!
我真该多多大声说出我的梦想
I should do out loud wishing more often.
那是玉米棒的味道吗
Is that a corn cob I spy?
我的小短腿
I got little legs!
嘿  苏斯  你好啊
Hey, Soos. What's up?
你有没有看见我的
Have you seen my--
呃  我等会儿再来吧
Uh... I'll come back later.
斯坦叔公  你快回来
Grunkle Stan, come back!
我还要干更多的坏事
I have more terrible things to do!
你惹大麻烦了  梅宝
You're toast, Mabel!
那间屋子差不多已经归我了
That room's as good as mine!
你在这儿呢  梅宝
There you are Mabel!
-爱的抱抱  -好哇
- Attack her with love! - Yeah!
睡衣派对
Sleep over!
什么  不不不
What!? No no no!
迪普  等等
Ahh! Dipper? Hey, wait!
等等  回来
Wait, come back!
嘿  我能和我的  姐姐说句话吗
Hey! Could I talk to my, uh, sister for a sec?
睡衣派对  男生免进
This is a sleepover buddy. No boys allowed!
姐妹们  我现在真的没什么心情参加你们的派对
Look guys, I'm not really in a sleepover mood right now.
我的女生小情绪正在闹别扭  懂吗
One of my irrational girl mood swings, you know?
有这种说法吧
Right? Don't we have those?
别介啊  我妈妈的成人爱情小说可不会
Come on! My mom's age-inappropriate romance novels
自己念出来给我们听
Aren't going to read themselves!
狼人  赤裸的胸膛
Oh! "Wolfman, barechest"!
真的么  我还是
Uh, really, I should probably..
来吧  你肯定会喜欢的
Come on! You know you love it!!!
我叫杰拉德
"My name is Gerard.
我是狼人  夜的种族
"I am a werewolf, creature of the night.
也是激情的种族
But I am also a creature of passion."
杰拉德好酷啊
Gerard is just so fierce.
发生什么事了  迪普
What's goin' on, Dipper?
哦  你是到了喜欢偷窥女生的尴尬年龄了吧
Ahh... you're at that creepy age where you spy on girls, huh?
看来咱俩该来场男人之间的谈话了
Guess it's time you and me had a man-to-man talk
关于初步的性教育什么的  懂吗
About the birds and the bees, ya know.
我为什么爱出汗
我还是去
I--I should really be going--
别想逃
No way out of it!
看着啊  都是这个小东西引发的
Look, it all begins with this little fella,
它叫脑垂体
The pituitary gland.
看上去很小  可是很有想法哦
He may be little, but he has big plans.
我想知道我会遇到什么好玩的东西
I wonder what rollicking adventures I'll stumble into.
一个泥潭
A mud puddle!
我敢打破传统吗
Do I dare live out the cliche?
我是头猪  哼哼  是吧
I'm a pig! Oink oink, right?
免费的午餐
Free meal!
不要  不要吃我
No! Don't eat me!
我是个被困在猪身体里的人
I'm a man trapped in a pig's body!
都这么说
That's what they all say!
救命啊  警察
Help! Police!
一个长着胡子的女巫在追赶一头会说话的猪
A bearded witch chasing a talking pig!
我的星座书说得真准
My horoscope came true.
读读我的
Now read mine!
-你是什么星座呢  双子座么  -你知道啊
- What are you, gemini? - You knew?!
我当然知道了
Yeah, of course, I knew!
现在你知道婴儿是从哪来的了
And now you know where babies come from.
再见了  我的童年
Goodbye, childhood.
我发觉你今天比以往都可爱
You know, I find you more likable today than usual.
估计最后赢的会是你啊
Maybe you could still win that game after all.
啥
Huh?
我原本打算把新房间给梅宝的
I was gonna give that new room to Mabel--
不不  你还是给梅宝吧
No, you should! Give it to Mabel!
你个混球
You big jerk!
你说什么
What did you say to me?
我说  给我闭嘴  老家伙
I said, uh, shut up, old man!
你又胖又蠢  你就是个蠢货
You're fat and dumb, and you're a dummy.
接招
And take that!
终于开始反驳我了  是吧
Finally Standing up to me, huh?
我喜欢
I love it!
知道吗  我已经决定了
You know, I've made up my mind.
新房间属于你了  迪普
The room belongs to you, Dipper.
不行啊
You can't!
你得把它给梅宝
You have to give it to Mabel!
嘘
Shh.
当你说“闭嘴老家伙”的时候就已经征服我了
You had me at "Shut up old man."
不
No!
结束
The end.
现在该读38部续集了
Now for the 38 sequels!
不要啊
No!
我要用你做培根
I'm gonna make you into bacon!
呀  听上去不错啊
Oh, ho! That sounds pretty good.
等等  我是说  不要啊
Wait, I mean, no!
三  四  五
Three, four, five.
是他  我的梦中情人
It's him! My dream date!
你好
Hello!?
你好  亲爱的  我是凯文
Hello baby, this is Kevin.
我的沙滩别墅还有间双人房
My beach house has room... for two.
凯文的声音听上去是机器人啊
Kevin has the voice of a robot.
别扫我兴  糖糖
Don't ruin this for me, Candy!
到你了  梅宝
It's your turn, Mabel.
我得赢回房间
I gotta win the room.
斯坦  是我  梅宝
Stan! It's me, Mabel!
我正在做你讨厌的事
I'm doing things you hate!
结束了  迪普
It's over, Dipper.
斯坦把房间给你了
Stan gave you the room.
哈哈  太好啦
Ha ha! Yes! All right!
咱俩把身体换回来吧  然后我就可以搬进去了
Well let's switch bodies then, and I can start moving in!
等会儿  只要你进不去
Wait a minute, you can't have the room...
你就永远不能拥有房间
If you can never get in!
嘿  回来
Hey, come back!
别闹了
Come on!
开门  迪普
Open the door, Dipper!
我是说  梅宝
I mean... Mabel.
我要怎么才能进去呢
How am I ever gonna get in there?
凯文  我最后再说一遍  我没兴趣
Kevin for the last time, I'm not interested!
你怎么能那样和凯文说话
How could you say that to Kevin!
姑娘们  谁想给我弟弟化个妆呢
Hey girls, who wants to give my brother a make-over!
很好  苏斯
Oh, good, Soos.
你有空吧
Ya got a second?
是这样的  现在日子不太好过  经济不景气啊之类的
Look, times are tough, economy, or something, etc.
重点就是  我要减你的薪水
Basically... I have to cut your pay.
你在干嘛
Wh-- what are you doing?
这是什么谈判策略吗
Is this some sort of negotiating tactic?
这些是没用的
'cause it's not gonna to work.
好吧  我刚是骗人的  我给你涨工资
Fine! I was lying. I'll give you a raise!
下次不要这样了
Just never do that again.
真是噩梦
Ugh. Nightmare.
能帮个忙么  我迷路了
Can you help me? I'm looking for directions--
你要给我带路吗
Oh, you'll show me the way?
真是个绅士啊
Such a gentleman!
我们是糖糖和格兰达
It's Candy and Grenda!
我的朋友们
Friends!
姐妹们
Hey guys!
你们好啊
What's up?
迪普  等等  不要让他进来
Dipper?! Wait! Don't let him in here!
开始化妆了哦
Make over!
别别  停下  不要
No, no! Stop, stop! Whoa, no!
我们要把你打扮得帅帅的
We're gonna make you so hot!
等下  不要
Wait, no! Stop!
你们听我说
Guys, you have to listen to me!
不要
No!
干得不错  姑娘们
Good job, ladies!
现在让我来加上最后一点
Now let me just add one final touch!
我的身体
My body!
我真是个天才
I'm a genius!
好了  梅宝
Ugh... all right, Mabel.
房间是我的了
The room is mine.
等等  暂停一下  刚刚发生了什么
Wait! Hold on here. What just happened?
我也不太明白
I barely understand it.
我只知道  如果你在这块地摊上蹭蹭脚
All I know, is if you shuffle your feet on this carpet,
你就可以和任何人交换身体
you can switch bodies or whatever.
-来个电  -不要啊
- Zip zip! - No!
拜托
Aw, come on!
我是个男生了
I am a boy now!
你好啊  哥们儿
What's up, brah?
咱再去弄点小胡子
Lets grow some moustaches!
迪普  把钥匙还给我
Dipper, give me that key back!
伙计们  别打了
Guys! Stop fighting!
我晕
Oh, no!
不过我似乎是第一次有肌肉了呢
Then again, I like having muscles for once
我的小手像洋娃娃的似的
Now I have tiny little doll hands!
大伙都听着
Everybody, look.
我们再给换回来  三 二
Swap back in three, two--
救命啊
Oh, dude!
回来  我要油炸你的耳朵
Come back! I wanna deep fry yer ears!
今晚的是宝宝战争节目
Tonight on baby fights!
在宝宝战争总部  麦迪逊和埃佛里之间
Tensions rise between madison and avery
的紧张局势正在升级
at baby fight headquartes.
我可不是来这儿交朋友的
把我的身体还回来
Give me my body back!
真棒  我变成圣诞老人了
Cool! I'm santa claus!
我又恢复天真无邪了
I've regained my innocence!
我猜我变成猪了
Well, I guess I'm a pig now.
这是个问题
So, that's a thing.
这个身体和我原先的那个
This body's not that different
没太大区别
From my old one.
我们接到报警说你们笑声太大
We got some reports of excessive giggling.
我的星座运程上可没预测到这些啊
My horoscope didn't say anything about this!
啊  我这是怎么了
Ahh! What's happening to me?!
我变成警察叔叔了
I am a police officer now!
我们去抓坏人吧  糖糖
Let's go get some perps, Candy!
-把钥匙还给我  梅宝  -休想
- Give me that key, Mabel! - Never!
梅宝  是你吗
Mabel, are you you?
嗯  是我
Yeah, I'm me.
我拿到钥匙啦
Well, I've got the key!
梅宝  房间是我的
Mabel! The room is mine!
给我
Give it to me!
你出什么毛病了
What's with you?
为什么非得要那个房间
Why do you need that room so bad?
我根本就没想过要搬出去
I never even wanted to move out!
我也是
Me either!
等等  什么  你再说一遍
Wait, what? Say that again!
我  我根本不想搬出去
I--I never wanted to move out.
那这都唱的是哪出啊
Then what was all this?
在你开始每晚往家里带朋友之前
Everything was fine until you started bringing
一切都挺好的
your friends around every night.
我是说  这个夏天和你一起玩挺有意思的
I mean, hanging out with you this summer's been fun.
但是现在  你总是和糖糖还有格兰达在一起
But now, you're always with Candy and Grenda.
我就像被你遗忘掉了
And I'm... like, just left behind.
哦  迪普
Aw, Dipper.
没事
It's okay.
我一直过得不开心
I've been having a hard time.
你不会理解我都经历了些什么
You wouldn't understand what I'm going through.
你是不是感觉尴尬易出汗
You're probably feeling awkward and sweaty, huh?
没错  你怎么知道的
Yeah. How'd you know?
给你  我不跟你争了
Here. I won't fight you for it.
谢了
Thanks.
看上去大家都恢复正常了
Well, it looks like everyone's back to normal!
除了苏斯  他是不是永远都是猪了
Except for Soos, who may be pig permanently?
不是  我也变回来了
Oh, no. I changed back.
至少我是这么觉着的
At least I think I did.
我还是要吃你
I'll still eat ya.
好了  伙计  玩够了
Okay pal, that's enough of that.
赶紧走吧  怪老头
Move it along, weird old man.
哈  我在想变成猪也没那么好
Huh, I guess being a pig wasn't that great after all.
嘿  我来给你挠挠你自己够不着的地儿
Hey, lemme get that spot you can never reach...
嘿  我想了很久  答案就是
Hey, I've been thinking and the answer is...
我答应了  我要嫁给你
Yes! I will marry you!
慢着  我不记得
Wait I don't remember anything about a--
那好吧
Hmm. All right.
好了
Ah, there.
男子汉有自己独立的房间了
Ahh, a man in his own space.
没错  不容易啊
That's right! Finally.
那你要拿这个旧东西怎么办
So what are you gonna do with this old thing?
丢掉
Get rid of it.
哈哈  说得好
Ha ha! You got it.
这地毯真难看
This carpet's ugly.
终于有我自己的房间了
Ah, finally, my own room.
晚安  梅宝
Goodnight, Mabel.
晚安  迪普
Goodnight, Dipper.
嘿  想一起来个睡衣派对么
Hey, um, you wanna have a sleepover?
小心了
Fore!
我为什么这么晚还要在外面晃荡呢
Ah! Why am I even out here at night?
你打算拿那间新房间怎么办呢
So, what are we gonna do with that new room?
我把它送给苏斯了
I gave it to Soos to replace
好让他从那间糟糕的休息室搬出去
that horrible break room he has.
嘿  你知道那个女士是怎么回事吗
Hey, do you know what the deal was with that lady?
我觉得我没办法答应你了
I just don't think I can do this anymore.
你看上去  就像变了个人
You just seem so... different.
是这样的  我之前遇到了点小麻烦
Look, dude, uh, I'm playing a little bit of catch up here.
那天我被困在一头猪的身体里了
I was in a pig's body for most of the day.
有什么问题么
What's going on?
我们还可以接吻吗
Can we kiss again?
这算不算是个选择
Is that an option?
哦  等等
Oh! Wait, wait.